Hey everyone, welcome back to another
lesson in this TSCA automation playlist.
Today I'm going to show you how you can
execute JavaScript on your browser using
one of the TSCA automation modules. So
there are some standard modules inside
the T-Box X engines and HTML where you
can find the modules called the execute
JavaScript and verify JavaScript result.
So using these two modules you can
either execute a particular JavaScript
or you can also verify the result of a
JavaScript. Okay.
So let's see how we can use this modules
uh to execute a javascript and then
verify the result of it. So u I am in my
test cases folder and I have already
created a test case called execute
javascript. Now inside this we are going
to drag the module or add the module.
Okay. So as I said uh it is under
standard modules tbox x engines and then
html. Here we'll find the two modules
execute JavaScript and verify JavaScript
result. Okay.
So, uh let's add these modules into our
test case. So, I'm going to drag the
execute JavaScript here first. And uh
then coming to module attributes for
this module uh we need to provide a
title of the window. uh this is the
browser window and then uh the
JavaScript the actual JavaScript which
you want to execute. Okay. So in title
I'm going to use a regular expression uh
which means it can be any title. Okay.
And then I'm going to write some
JavaScript right here. So I'm going to
use window dot location dot href. Okay.
And then I'm going to use uh the actual
web page here. Right. So I've already
copied this website uh source demo. This
is what I want to open. And this is the
JavaScript which we want to execute. So
let's go ahead and execute this now. So
run this in scratchbook.
And now uh we will get an error here.
Okay. So in the log info you can see uh
that it is asking to define a test
configuration parameter for browser and
also enter the actual browser on which
we want to perform this. Okay. So this
is a mandatory requirement. If you don't
do this then you will get this uh
invalid operation exception. Okay. So
let's go into our test case. Go to the
test configuration tab here. Uh we are
going to add a new test configuration
parameter called browser.
And then uh we are going to choose the
Chrome browser right here. Okay. Now
let's go ahead and execute this again.
Now you can see in the background it has
uh redirected your web page to source
demo.com on the Chrome browser and our
test case has actually passed. So it was
able to execute the particular
JavaScript. Right? So this is how you
can execute any particular JavaScript.
uh either it is to move to a particular
web page or performing some actions on
your web elements. So any JavaScript uh
which can be done on the browser uh you
can execute it right here using this
module.
Now the next module which we want to
check is the verify JavaScript result.
So let's add another test case here to
verify JavaScript.
Okay. And then I'm going to add the
module here called verify JavaScript
result.
And here again um you need to provide a
title. Uh then the JavaScript and then
the result. Okay. Which has got an
action mode verify. So it is going to
perform a verification. Okay. So let's
first see what we want to verify here.
Okay. So what I want to do is I want to
verify uh some cookies from the website.
Okay. So let's check on the website what
cookies are available here. Okay. So I'm
going to go to uh developer tools
and uh right here uh I'm going to find
the cookies for this particular website.
Okay. So currently there are no cookies.
But if I'm going to enter some standard
user right here and uh the password.
Now if I login into this website you
will see that a session cookie has been
created called session username and the
value for this is standard user and that
is what I want to verify from the
JavaScript. Okay. So let's go back here
and in the title I'm going to give a
star again and then in the JavaScript I
am going to say return
document dot cookie.
Okay. So what it is going to do is it is
going to return uh the cookie which is
present in that HTML document and then I
want to verify whether that cookie
contains uh the username. Okay. So we
have to give the cookie name here which
is session username and value standard
user. Okay. So let's go here and then uh
we are going to say session username
equals uh and then we are going to copy
this standard user.
Okay. So write here standard
user. So this is the cookie which is
present here and this is what we want to
verify. Okay. So let's go ahead and
execute this now.
Okay. Uh the same error again. Uh I
should have done this at the folder
level not at the test case level. Okay.
So let's do one thing. Uh for now I will
just add it here as well. But ideally we
should have done that at a folder level.
Okay. So, browser and Chrome and then
let's go ahead and execute this now.
And you will see the verification was
successful. Uh this was the expected
value and this was the actual value.
Okay. So, this way you can also verify
some results uh which is returned from
your JavaScript using this particular
module. So these are the two modules
which are present in the TSCOA
automation modules under HTML engine and
this you can use to execute in
JavaScript or verify the result of the
JavaScript.
That's all for this particular video. If
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments. If you like this
video then please subscribe to our
channel. Thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next video.